

Mário Patrão

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Hi, I'm Mário. A Portuguese web developer living in London for the past 7 years. As a web developer with 10 years of experience I'm now looking to embrace a new challenge that will allow me to grasp new technologies, augment my know-how and work with different "mind-sets".

SKILLS

Angular, JavaScript
C#, .NET, Microsoft Dyanmics
HTML 5
SQL Server, MySQL
Git, Team Foundation Server
Umbraco, Wordpress
Agile developement
Client liaison

CONTACT

mariopatrao@gmail.com +44 (0)7999 061551 Flat 5 Hexham Lodge 10-12 Mildmay Park N1 4PG, London

HOBBIES

Skate, gigs and pub quizzes

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER @ Wealth Dynamix

March 2018 - To date

I started at WDX as a front-end developer working with angular to help the product team to upgrade the core project.

As I grew withtin the company I was moved to a senior position and work with the client teams working very closely with the lead developers in providing the best solution to our different clients. On my client work and projects I'm using the current tech stack:

- Add and refactor WDX WEB API using C# and .NET WEB API 2;
- Work within the clients Microsoft CRM Dynamics solutions;
- Create new and expand current components using Angular (currently version 5) and JSON;

Adding to my role, I'm also part of the senior development team. My responsibilities within this group include:

- Working with the other senior and lead developers in upgrading our product, this includes updates to angular version, updates to our testing solution, test new frameworks to improve some core functionality;
- Managing a range of mid-level developers. This includes having regular 1-2-1 meetings and work with them on their personal goals at WDX while reporting directly to the Head of Solutions Architecture and the Operations Director;
- Mentoring junior developers as part of the WDX Buddy Program;
- Prepare and present company-wide KT sessions. These sessions could be technical (Angular and C#), or can be know-hows/best practices/demos for new functionalities added to our core product.

WEB DEVELOPER @ CTN Group

December 2014 - December 2017

At CTN I am integral to all aspects of the delivery of our client's digital projects. This includes:

- Back-end coding (mainly C#)
- Front-end coding of our client facing websites (Razor, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap)
- Implementation of webcasting platforms provisioned for the delivery of CTN's client's webcasting services
- Development of CTN's internal tools, from scoping through to delivery of the final product
- Maintain CTN digital infrastructure
- Working with brand consultants following a CTN rebrand to create a new vibrant website which can be viewed at https://embolden.agency/

I have worked with large blue-chip clients including M&S, Unilever, GlaxoSmithKline, RSA, GM&T among many others. On most occasions I am the direct contact for the client and work with them from conception to final delivery and execution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER @ ELEMENT 3 SOFTWARE

May 2012 - December 2014

At Element 3 I worked on different web solutions for housing developers to track end to end sales opportunities.

We also wrote a new web based document manager named FileHound. All this projects were written to be responsive and fast to convince large organizations to move their workflow into modern web based platforms.

WEB DEVELOPER @ PLANETA VIRTUAL

June 2009 - March 2012

Planeta Virtual is a software house specialized in web solutions. Its main product is a web solution that is responsible for the human resources, accounting and CRM implemented in several companies. I was responsible for multiple projects through the whole development cycle.

EDUCATION

INFORMATICS ENGINEERING @ FACULTY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF THE UNIVERSITY FERNANDO PESSOA OF PORTO

September 2002 - January 2009

COMPUTER SYSTEM ENGINEERING @ THE ACADEMY OF HUMANITIES AND ECONOMICS IN LODZ

September 2006 — July 2007